Mss.B.J44 Mss.B.J44
American Philosophical Society
- Selected Inventory from Genetics Subject Guide
  - Pearl, Raymond, 1899-1933; Correspondence ( 278 items )
    Biographical and personal data; Davenport, Charles Benedict; Editorial matters; Eugenics; Evolution; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Johns Hopkins University; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; National Academy of Sciences; Philosophy of science; Political issues; Poultry genetics; Protozoan genetics; Publication; Research support; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Statistics, biostatistics, biometrics -- Pearson, Karl; Travel -- Europe; United States Fish Commission; University of Maine; University of Pennsylvania
  - Reighard, Jacob, 1897-1933; Correspondence ( 29 items )
    Biographical and personal data; Publication -- The Anatomy of the Cat; Recommendations -- Jennings, Herbert Spencer; Teaching; United States Fish Commission; University of Michigan
  - International Congress of Zoology. Seventh Congress, 1907; Records ( 196 items )
    Conferences and symposia; International Congress of Zoology -- Seventh Congress; Zoology -- Animal behavior
  - Shull, George Harrison, 1918-1923; Correspondence ( 72 items )
    Business; Conferences and symposia; Editorial matters -- Genetics; International Congress of Eugenics; International Congress of Genetics; Morgan, Thomas Hunt; Political issues; Publication -- Genetics; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs
  - Sonneborn, Tracy M., 1926-1973; Correspondence ( 163 items )
    Biographical and personal data; Chen, T. T.; Conferences and symposia; Displaced German scholars -- Jollos, Victor; Fellowships, assistantships; Graduate study; Indiana University; Jennings, Herbert Spencer -- Second marriage; Johns Hopkins University; Kimball, Richard Fuller; Lynch, Ruth Stocking; MacDougal, Daniel Trembly; Marine Biological Laboratory, Woods Hole; Mast, Samuel Ottmar; Moewus, Franz; National Academy of Sciences; Preer, John R.; Protozoan genetics; Protozoan genetics -- Paramecium mating types; Publication; Scientific organizations, meetings, programs; Teaching; Travel -- Great Britain; Travel -- Japan; University of California, Los Angeles; World War II -- Impact on science
  - Williams and Wilkins Company, 1918-1936; Correspondence ( 56 items )
    Kammerer, Paul; Publication; Shull, George Harrison
  - Wilson, Edwin Bidwell, 1920-1959; Correspondence ( 9 items )
    Harvard University -- Bussey Institute; Pearl, Raymond
  - Yerkes, Robert M., 1899-1940; Correspondence ( 46 items )
    Johns Hopkins University; Protozoan genetics -- Protozoan behavior; Psychobiology; Publication; Zoology
  - Young, Aldie Jennings, 1895-1897, 1934; Manuscripts ( 10 items )
    Biographical and personal data -- Jenks family; Burridge, Mary Louise; Harvard University; Jennings, Herbert Spencer -- Cultural life; Travel -- Europe
- Papers
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, April 4, 1934; 11x8-1/2; Abel, John Jacob, 1857-1938
    Scope and Contents note
    Baltimore, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Certificate of membership to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Jan. 16, 1906; 13-1/2x19; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Printed D.S.: Samuel G. Dixon, pres., Arthur Bevan and Edwin G. Conklin, vice pres., and J.Percy Moore and Edward J. Nolan, secs. 1p. (see H. S. Jennings papers.)
  - Certificate of membership issued to Herbert Spencer Jennings, March 19, 1918; 13-1/2 x 19; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: John Cadwalader, pres., Edwin G. Conklin and Henry Skinner, vice pres., J. Percy Moore,and Edward J. Nolan, secs. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Corresponding member.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Baltimore, Dec. 15, 1923; 11x8-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S.: J. Percy Moore. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Thanks for his address on Leidy.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Nov. 25, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Typed L. 2p. (see H.S.Jennings papers.) Describes the workings of the academy during the war.
  - Letter to H.S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Dec. 8, 1942; 11x8-1/2 and 6-1/4x5-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S.: Charles M.B. Cadwalader. 1p.and receipt. (see H.S.Jennings Papers.) Thanks for contribution to the academy.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Sept. 11, 1944; 11x8-1/2; Academy of Natural Sciences of Philadelphia
    L.S.: Charles M.B.Cadwalader. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for contribution.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Nov. 10, 1923; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Adams, A Elizabeth
    Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks reprint of a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Nov. 26, 1923; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Adams, A Elizabeth
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Thanks for publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Nov. 19, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    Los Angeles, New York, Typed L.S. 1p.and enc.of 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks him to contribute a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Nov. 26, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    Los Angeles, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S.Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Jan.10, 1942; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) May use cuts.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Feb. 2, 1942; 11X8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, March 2, 1942; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, June 11, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Scientific subjects.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, July 21, 1942; 11x8-1/2x; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. Enc.of 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Encloses circular letter about a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] H.[sic] Jennings, July 30, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    Los Angeles, New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning death in cells.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, July 30, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Alexander, Jerome, b. 1876
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Scientific matters.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Dec. 16, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Allers, Rudolf, 1883-1963
    Washington, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning publication of their book.
  - Letter to Herbert Spencer Jennings, May 13, 1914; 11-1/2x9-1/2; American Academy of Arts and Sciences
    Boston, Printed L.filled in in ms.S.: Edwin H. Hall. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Has been elected fellow.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Dec. 12, 1921; 11x8-1/2; American Association for the Advancement of Science
    Mimeographed L. 1p.and enc.of 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concernings his paper to be read at the 1922 meeting.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Dec. 1, 1938; 11x8-1/2; American Association for the Advancement of Science.
    Washington, Typed L.S.: F.R.Moulton. 1p.and enc.of 2 leaves. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the meeting and the papers which his group will present.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Dec. 12, 1940; 11x8-1/2; American Philosophical Society
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S.: Edwin G. Conklin. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Wishes him to prepare obituary notice for Raymond Pearl.
  - Letter to Herbert Spencer Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 9, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Anderson, Harold H. (Harold Homer), 1897-
    Urbana, I11., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the lecture he delivered at the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Berkeley, May 22, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Angell, Donald K
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the bicentennial celebration of U of P.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, June 16, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Aronson, Moses Judah
    New York, A.L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning an article for publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, April 22, 1920; 11x8-1/2; Badger, Richard G
    Boston, Typed L.S. 1p., end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Business.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, April 18, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Baily, Joshua Longstreth, 1889-
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning an obituary notice for Raymond Pearl.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, April 27, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Baily, Joshua Longstreth, 1889-
    (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning obituary notice of Raymond Pearl.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Dec. 26, 1924; 10-1/2x8 and 13-1/2x6; Baker, Horace Greeley, 1873-
    Iowa City, Typed L. 2p.and enc. of 2p. (see H. S. Jennings papers) Concerning a proposed volume on evolution.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Sept. 24, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Bangson, John Stuver, 1889-
    Berea, Ky., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for reprints of articles.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Jan. 21, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Banta, Arthur M. (Arthur Mangun), 1877-1946
    Providence, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Nov. 16, 1923; 10x7 and 5-1/2x8-1/2; Banta, George, publishing co., Menasha, Wis.
    Menasha, Wis., Typed L.S.: C.A. Purenhoom. 1p., end. and 1p.receipt dated: Jan. 15, 1924. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning his publication on genetics.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Sept. 6, 1930; 11x8-1/2; Barnes, Elsie
    Culver City, Cal., A.L.S. 3p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Comments on his work on eugenics.
  - Letter to Ma [Mrs. Barrett], March 9, 1934; 11x8-1/2; Barrett, Roscoe J
    Chicago, A.L.S. 3p.and P.S.by Helen [Barrett]. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter. Refers to Jennings.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Nov. 2, 1939; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Belda, Walter Henry, 1903-
    A.L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Herbert Spencer Jennings, Los Angles, Oct. 4, 1941; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Bensinger, George C
    Pottsville, Pa., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for reprints.
  - Letter to Herbert Spencer Jennings, Baltimore, Sept. 4, 1930; 11x8-1/2; Billikopf, Jacob, 1883-1950
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Congratulates him on his book on eugenics.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Dec. 16, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Blakeslee, Albert Francis, 1874-1954
    Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning publication of a speech.
  - Letter to Herbert [S.] Jennings, Los Angeles, Aug. 27, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Blumer, Herbert, 1900-1987
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Would like to publish his article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 21, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Blumer, Herbert, 1900-1987
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Will not publish articles.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Los Angeles, Dec. 18, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Boring, Edwin Garrigues, 1886-1968
    Cambridge, Typed L.S. 2p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning studies on paramecia.
  - Certificate of membership to Herbert S. Jennings, April 16, 1901; 15x19; Boston Society of Natural History
    Printed D.filled in in ms.S.: Charles S. Minot, pres. and Charles F. Batchelder, sec. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.)
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, May 22, 1918; 11x8-1/2; Boyd, Paul Prentice, 1877-
    Lexington,Ky., Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a job for Cowles.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings. Baltimore, Oct. 10, 1924; 11x8-1/2; Breitenbecker, J K
    Woods Hole, Mass.,Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Congratulates him on an article.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Baltimore, July 31, 1939; 10-1/2x7-1/4; Brennemann, Joseph, 1872-
    Chicago, Typed L.S.with initials. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the possible revision of a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, June 10, 1921; 7-1/4x8-1/2; Brentano's (Firm)
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Walt. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning one of his early publications.(on genetics?).
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Aug. 7, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Broadhurst, Jean, 1873-1954
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Wishes to use an illustration from one of his articles.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Sept. 22, 1930; 6x8-1/2 and 9x6; Brooklyn society for ethical culture
    Brooklyn, A.L.S. 1p.and enc.of 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, July 9, 1925; 11x8-1/2; Brooks, Fowler D. (Fowler Dell), b. 1885
    New York, A.L.S. 2p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for reprints of an article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, March 29, 1924; 11x8-1/2; Buchholz, Heinrich Ewald, 1879-1955
    Baltimore, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings Papers.) Concerning sociological studies.
  - Letter to Herbert Spencer Jennings, Baltimore, May 2, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Bull, Nina, b. 1880
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning reactions.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, New York, Sept. 29, 1924; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Burbank, Luther, 1849-1926
    Santa Rosa, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H. S. Jennings Papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 16, 1924; 5-1/2x8-1/2; Burbank, Luther, 1849-1926
    Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Baltimore, June 13, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Burnet, Philip
    Wilmington, Typed L.S. 4p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks questions concerning environment vs. heredity.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Ocean City, Md., June 21, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Burnet, Philip
    Typed L.S. 5p. (see H.S.Jennings papers.) Concerning the psychology of salesmanship.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Ocean City, Md., June 28, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Burnet, Philip
    Wilmington, Typed L.S. 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter. Concerning intelligence.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Sept. 13, 1921; 11x8-1/2; Burnet, Philip
    Wilmington, Typed L.S. 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, June 18, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Butler, Elmer Grimshaw, 1900-
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a proposed meeting.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Sept. 30, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Butler, Elmer Grimshaw, 1900-
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning titles of papers to be read.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 5, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Butler, Elmer Grimshaw, 1900-
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning papers which are to be read.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 21, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Butler, Elmer Grimshaw, 1900-
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning papers to be read at a meeting.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Nov. 1, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Butler, Elmer Grimshaw, 1900-
    Princeton, Typed L.S. 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the AAAS meeting.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 4, 1920; 8x5; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 29, 1937; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings Papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to [Herbert S. Jennings], Jan. 13, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L. 1p.and enc. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a proposed publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 31, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
  - Letter to [Herbert S. Jennings;], 1938; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    Typed L.S. 2p. (see H.S.Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, April 1, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Berkeley, April 14, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Aug. 14, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a possible publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Aug. 17, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    Woods Hole, Mass., Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 16, 1939; 8x5-1/4; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Business.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Dec. 19, 1939; 8x5; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
  - Outline of proposed volume on protozoa, [1938]; 11x8-1/2; Calkins, Gary N. (Gary Nathan), b. 1869
    Typed D. 3p. Copy. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) One article to be written by H.S. Jennings.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Los Angeles, July 6, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Calvert, Philip Powell, b. 1871
    Philadelphia, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Delighted he is to participate in the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Oct. 22, 1924; 6-1/2x5; Cambell, Evelyn Cushing
    New York; A.L.S. 2p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for a reprint.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Sept. 30, 1939; 8-1/2x5-1/2; Carper, L
    Baltimore, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, June 5, 1925; 11x8-1/2; Cartwright, B. W. (Bertram William), b. 1890
    Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for reprint of an article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, June 30, 1925; 11x8-1/2; Cartwright, B. W. (Bertram William), b. 1890
    Winnepeg, man., A.L.S. 1p. (see H.S.Jennings papers.) Scientific news.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Nov. 8, 1924; 7-1/4x8-1/2; Cason, Hulsey, 1893-
    Syracuse, N.Y. A.L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks for reprint of an article.
  - Invitation to [Herbert S. Jennings] to attend the semicentennial celebration, 1939; 8-1/4x6-1/2; Catholic University of America
    Engraved D. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.)
  - Letter to H[erbert] J.[sic] Jennings, Los Angeles, Feb. 17, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Catholic University of America
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Joseph Corrigan. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks him to write a chapter for a publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 19, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Catholic University of America
    Washington, Typed L.S.: Joseph Corrigan. 1p.and enc.of 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Forwards payment for article.
  - Program for a symposium, [Oct.], 1939; 11x8-1/2; Catholic University of America
    Typed D. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) H.S. Jennings to deliver a lecture.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Sept. 13, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    Garrison, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Would like to print lecture which he will give at U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Berkeley, Oct. 12, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    Garrison, N.Y., Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Wishes to publish lecture delivered at the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 28, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James Mckeen, 1860-1944
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning publication of his paper delivered at the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Nov. 1, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    New York, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the article he read at the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Dec. 11, 1940; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    New York, Typed L.S.with initials. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the publication of his address at the U of P bicentennial celebration.
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Oct. 2, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
    Garrison, N.Y., Typed L.S.with initials. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Will publish his article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Oct. 25, 1941; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, James McKeen, 1860-1944
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Jan. 13, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, Jaques, 1904-
    Lancaster, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Would like to print some articles.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Jan. 19, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, Jaques, 1904-
    Lancaster, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning the publication of an article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Dec. 8, 1939; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, Jaques, 1904-
    Lancaster, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning reprints of an article.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, Aug. 10, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, Jaques, 1904-
    Lancaster, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Forwards publication.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Nov. 28, 1938; 11x8-1/2; Cattell, Jaques, 1904-1960
    Lancaster, Typed L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning publication of some articles
  - Letter to Herbert S. Jennings, Jan. 22, 1924; 6-1/4x5; Chamberlain, W L
    Meriden, Conn., A.L.S. 3p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Would like to obtain a copy of his paper on evolution and Mendelism.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 4, 1933; 11x8-1/2; Child, Charles Manning, 1869-1954
    Chicago, Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Friendly letter.
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Los Angeles, April 14, 1942; 11x8-1/2; Cincinnati social hygiene society
    Cincinnati, Typed L.S.: Roy E. Dickerson. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Concerning mating habits of animals.
  - Diploma to Herbert Spencer Jennings, Sept. 10, 1909; 17x13-3/4; Clark University (Worcester, Mass.)
    Worcester, Mass., D.S.: A.G. Bulloch and 11 others. 1p. Parchment. (see H.S. Jennings papers.)
  - Letter to H[erbert] S. Jennings, Baltimore, Jan. 29, 1924; 3-1/4x5-1/2; Clark, Hubert Lyman, 1870-1947
    Cambridge, A.L.on postal card. 1p.and add., end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Thanks for publications, especially the one on immigration.
  - The influence of mixing cultures on conjugation., May, 1926; 11x8-1/2; Clark, Leonard B. (Leonard Bertand), 1902-1986
    Typed D. 5p.and end.by J.S.Jennings. (see H.S.Jennings papers.)
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Baltimore, Oct. 17, 1932; 11x8-1/2; Clower, T A
    A.L.S. 1p. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Asks question concerning a publication.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Dec. 31, 1923; 6x5; Cochran, Lucile
    Typed L.S. 1p.,end. (see H.S. Jennings papers.) Thanks for publication sent to Mrs. E.H. Harriman.
  - Letter to [Herbert S.] Jennings, Nov. 22, 1940; 9-1/2x6; Coe, Wesley R. (Wesley Roswell), 1869-1960